

**UX Designer & Researcher** 

jamesdavidmoffet.com jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com jamesdavidmoffet

## about

As a designer and researcher, I am obsessed with understanding the human mechanisms by which technology can deliver us into an alternative future. As a researcher, I have learned to temper this obsession, harnessing critical theory and a range of research and management techniques that help me to redirect the internal inertia of established organizations and to find room to apply systems-level, user-centered thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's lives.

## education

2016 - 2018

## Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's degree, Design Technology Studies

## SKIIS

Design Research
UI/UX Design
Data Science
Software Engineering
Hardware Engineering
Public Speaking
Project Management
Product Design

# work experience

### OutVote.io

2017 - 2018 Cambridge, MA, USA Director of User Experience
 In 2017, Outvote acquired my civtech
 startup COMM!T and grew to a team of
 I direct an agile team of designers,
 coders and researchers to ensure that
 we ship a product that meets the needs
 of 10 enterprise clients and 1000 users.

### **Independent Consulting**

2016-2018 Cambridge, MA, USA

### UXD/UXR Consultant

Collaborated with GoINVO on the MA SNAP web application redesign.
Consulted for City of Boston on FOIA process redesign. Designed open source citizen analytics apps for Cambridge.

## MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA

### - Research Manager

Led team of 12 researchers, designers and devs. Conducted field/remote user research on 1,200 grassroots organizing groups. Designed, built and deployed a collaborative mapping tool to help orgs discover each other and connect.

### **Fulbright Fellow**

2015 - 2016 Budapest, HU

#### Design Lecturer

Lectured at CEU and piloted OpenLab public design workshops, mentoring UXR, interface design and service prototyping for public projects.

#### SEIU

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA

### - Senior UX and Product Manager

Built a user-centered design and engineering team from the ground up, replaced 20-plus-yr-old software products handling all critical financial and constituent data for 10% net revenue gain